<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ottawa COVID-19 Projections on Ottawa COVID19</title>
    <link>https://613covid.ca/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ottawa COVID-19 Projections on Ottawa COVID19</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://613covid.ca/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Methods</title>
      <link>https://613covid.ca/model/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://613covid.ca/model/</guid>
      <description>Described below is a brief description of methods, data and model parameters used at 613covid.ca. More detailed information can be found in the accompanying references.
Projection models All data used to create projection models can be accessed at Open Ottawa. See ’COVID-19 cases and deaths`.
Covid-19 short-term projections are created using the Bayesian EpiNow2 model developed by the EpiForecasts team.
 Projections are based on observed covid-19 cases by reporting date, which is, in turn, estimated using reported incubation period and consideration for reporting delays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://613covid.ca/more/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://613covid.ca/more/</guid>
      <description>Model use There are two main uses of the projections:
Short-term projections (1 to 4 weeks) reflect the current level of covid-19 transmssion and current effectivess of ongoing covid-19 prevention and control. Short-term projections the immediate need health care such hospital and critical care services for COVID-19 patients.
 Long-term projections (6 weeks onward) reflect sustain trends in covid-19 transmissions. Long-term projections are helpful to assess the potiential effect of covid-19 re-opening or the need of increased restrictions to control surges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changelog</title>
      <link>https://613covid.ca/change-log/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://613covid.ca/change-log/</guid>
      <description>Updates involving only data updates will no longer be documented.
V3.3.0 2020-11-26
 Short-term case projections added to the homepage. See More for a discussion about model interpretation and Methods for how the projections where created.   V3.2.0 2020-10-27
 Updates to wastewater page.   V3.1.0 2020-10-13
 Wastewater page added describing covid-19 wastewater surveillance.   V3.0.0 2020-10-05
 Case data &amp;amp; projections have been added to the website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://613covid.ca/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://613covid.ca/contact/</guid>
      <description>Media contact: Michaela Schreiter, Media Relations Officer, The Ottawa Hospital, mschreiter@toh.ca ph: 613-222-7674
Science contacts: Doug Manuel dmanuel@ohri.ca, Warsame Yusuf waryusuf@ohri.ca, Alan Forster
Acknowledgements for website and content: Warsame Yusuf, Rostyslav Vyuha, Yulric Sequeira, Andrew Fitches, and others on Big Life Lab team.
Supporting Ottawa Public Health epidemiologists: Amira Ali, Jacqueline Willmore, Dara Spatz
uOttawa – CHEO SARS-CoV-2 research group: Robert Delatolla, Alex MacKenzie, Patrick D’Aoust, Élisabeth Mercier, Antoine Cantin, Tyson Graber</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ottawa covid-19 wastewater surveillance</title>
      <link>https://613covid.ca/wastewater/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://613covid.ca/wastewater/</guid>
      <description>The National Capital Region is the first community in Canada to conduct and report daily wastewater readings of SARS-CoV-2 viral signal to help inform its community response in the fight against covid-19, thanks to innovative research from the CHEO Research Institute and the University of Ottawa.
People with covid-19 shed the causative SARS-CoV-2 virus in their stool, regardless of whether they have symptoms, receive a covid-19 test or ever are diagnosed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ottawa covid-19 wastewater surveillance (development page)</title>
      <link>https://613covid.ca/wastewater_dev/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://613covid.ca/wastewater_dev/</guid>
      <description>The National Capital Region is the first community in Canada to conduct and report daily wastewater readings of Cov-V2 viral signal to help inform its community response in the fight against covid-19, thanks to innovative research from the CHEO Research Institute (CHEO RI) and the University of Ottawa (uOttawa).
People with covid-19 shed the causative SARS-CoV-2 virus in their stool, regardless of whether they have symptoms, receive a covid-19 test or ever are diagnosed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://613covid.ca/roadmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://613covid.ca/roadmap/</guid>
      <description>  The main purpose of this site is to visualize Ottawa-based projections for models performed by other teams.
 Review and update model parameters based on recent published studies. Priories for review:  ventilated patients deaths   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short-term case projections for Ottawa (development page)</title>
      <link>https://613covid.ca/short-proj-dev/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://613covid.ca/short-proj-dev/</guid>
      <description>Dashboard (part of the main page dashboard)
Case doubling time: 62.4 days
 Introduction (text will go after observed data)
Short-term and long-term covid-19 projections are presented below. See More for a discussion about model interpretation and Methods for how the projections where created. Short-term projections reflect current covid-19 transmission; while long-term projections reflect sustained transmission trends. Short-term and long-term projections can trend in different directions when there are changing patterns of community covid-19 transmission.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
