<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projections relatives à la COVID-19 à Ottawa on Ottawa COVID19</title>
    <link>https://613covid.ca/fr/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projections relatives à la COVID-19 à Ottawa on Ottawa COVID19</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://613covid.ca/fr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Methods</title>
      <link>https://613covid.ca/fr/model/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://613covid.ca/fr/model/</guid>
      <description>Described below is a brief description of methods, data and model parameters used at 613covid.ca. More detailed information can be found in the accompanying references.
Projection models All data used to create projection models can be accessed at Open Ottawa. See ’COVID-19 cases and deaths`.
COVID-19 short-term projections are created using the Bayesian EpiNow2 model developed by the EpiForecasts team.
 Projections are based on observed COVID-19 cases by reporting date, which is, in turn, estimated using reported incubation period and consideration for reporting delays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://613covid.ca/fr/more/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://613covid.ca/fr/more/</guid>
      <description>Utilisation des modèles Les projections s’utilisent principalement de deux manières :
Les projections à court terme (2 à 4 semaines) servent à connaître les besoins immédiats en services hospitaliers et en soins critiques pour les patients atteints de la COVID-19.
Les projections à long terme (6 semaines ou plus) servent à évaluer l’effet d’un relâchement de la distanciation physique.
 Précision des modèles Il est difficile de faire des projections précises à long terme sur la propagation de la COVID-19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changelog</title>
      <link>https://613covid.ca/fr/change-log/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://613covid.ca/fr/change-log/</guid>
      <description>V3.6.0 2022-02-24
 Hospital projections added to homepage.   V3.5.0 2022-01-28
 Wastewater projections and growth estimates added to Wastewater page.   V3.4.0 2021-06-16
 Updates to the Wastewater page. Variant plot updated to include a midpoint rolling average. Details on variants of interest/concern detection included in page.   V3.3.3 2021-04-08
 Plot added to the Wastewater page visualizing proportion of variant B.1.1.7 RNA detected in wastewater.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://613covid.ca/fr/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://613covid.ca/fr/contact/</guid>
      <description>Personne-ressource pour les médias: Michaela Schreiter, agente des relations avec les médias, L’Hôpital d’Ottawa. Courriel: mschreiter@toh.ca Téléphone: 613-222-7674
Personnes-ressources scientifiques: Doug Manuel dmanuel@ohri.ca, Alan Forster
Remerciements pour le site Web et le contenu: Warsame Yusuf, Rostyslav Vyuha, Yulric Sequeira, Gauri Saran, Andrew Fitches et les autres membres de l’équipe de Big Life Lab.
Avec le soutien des épidémiologistes de Santé publique Ottawa: Amira Ali, Jacqueline Willmore, Dara Spatz
Groupe de recherche uOttawa – CHEO SARS-CoV-2: Robert Delatolla, Alex MacKenzie, Patrick D’Aoust, Élisabeth Mercier, Antoine Cantin, Tyson Graber.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ottawa COVID-19 wastewater surveillance</title>
      <link>https://613covid.ca/fr/wastewater/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://613covid.ca/fr/wastewater/</guid>
      <description>People with COVID-19 shed the causative SARS-CoV-2 virus in their stool, regardless of whether they have symptoms, receive a COVID-19 test or ever are diagnosed. Thus, in contrast to assessing community COVID-19 levels by measuring the number of active cases, which may miss asymptomatic infections as well as be subject to limited test availability, wastewater surveillance consistently captures most of the population with COVID-19 given that everyone goes to the washroom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://613covid.ca/fr/roadmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://613covid.ca/fr/roadmap/</guid>
      <description> The main purpose of this site is to visualize Ottawa-based projections for models performed by other teams.
 Review and update model parameters based on recent published studies. Priories for review:  ventilated patients deaths   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>