<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ottawa COVID Projections on Ottawa COVID19</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ottawa COVID Projections on Ottawa COVID19</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Model parameters</title>
      <link>/model/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/model/</guid>
      <description>Projections are based on the reported daily hospital census for Ottawa.
 Daily hospital use reported by Ottawa Public Health.  Model parameters other than Ottawa hospital use are aligned with other models.
 Model parameters are described below.
 Parameter estimates are from COVID-19-MC and Tuite, Fisman, et al. models where possible, with updates based on Verity et al. (Lancet, March 20, 2020)* and Ferguson et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/more/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/more/</guid>
      <description>Model use There are two main uses of the projections:
Short-term projections (2 to 4 weeks) to inform the immediate need for hospital and critical care services for COVID-19 patients.
 Long-term projections (6 weeks onward) to assess the effect of relaxing physical distancing.
   Model accuracy Creating accurate, long-range projections to predict the spread COVID-19 is difficult. It’s akin to forecasting when a hurricane will make landfall when it is still thousands of kilometers out at sea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changelog</title>
      <link>/change-log/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/change-log/</guid>
      <description>Updates involving only data updates will no longer be documented.
V2.0.1 2020-05-11
 Updated TOH census data to 2020-05-10. Minor changes to model parameters:  sd_percent_change_current changed from 1.1 to 1. sd_percent_change_reduction_20 changed from 0.9 to 0.8. Previously these parameters were modified to correct for hospitalizations of long-term care home patients.  Documentation on why ICU and death projections have been removed.   V2.0.0 2020-05-07
 Replaced Ottawa hospital census data with The Ottawa Hospital (TOH) census data to 2020-05-05.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>Media contact: Michaela Schreiter, Media Relations Officer, The Ottawa Hospital, mschreiter@toh.ca ph: 613-222-7674
Science contacts: Doug Manuel dmanuel@ohri.ca, Warsame Yusuf waryusuf@ohri.ca, Alan Forster
Acknowledgements for website and content: Warsame Yusuf, Rostyslav Vyuha, Yulric Sequeira, Andrew Fitches, and others on Big Life Lab team.
Supporting Ottawa Public Health epidemiologist: Amira Ali, Jacqueline Willmore, Dara Spatz
Attribution: COVID-19 icons made by surang from www.flaticon.com.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roadmap</title>
      <link>/roadmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/roadmap/</guid>
      <description> The main purpose of this site is to visualize Ottawa-based projections for models performed by other teams.
 Review and update model parameters based on recent published studies. Priories for review:  ventilated patients deaths   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>