<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ottawa COVID Projections on Ottawa COVID19</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ottawa COVID Projections on Ottawa COVID19</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Model parameters</title>
      <link>/model/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/model/</guid>
      <description>Projections are based on the reported daily hospital census for Ottawa.
 Census is defined as the number of hospitalized patients each day
 Daily hospital use reported by Ottawa Public Health. There is discussion to incorporate regional data rather than just cases from Ottawa hospitals.
 Doubling time (time it takes for the number of hospitalized COVID-19 patients to double) of 3 days from March 17 to 25, 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/more/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/more/</guid>
      <description>Model use There are two main uses of the projections:
Short-term projections (2 to 4 weeks) to inform the immediate need for hospital and critical care services for COVID-19 patients.
 Long-term projections (6 weeks to 10 months) to assess how to ‘flatten the curve’.
   Model accuracy Creating accurate, long-range projections to predict the spread COVID-19 is difficult. It’s akin to forecasting when a hurricane will make landfall when it is still thousands of kilometers out at sea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changelog</title>
      <link>/change-log/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/change-log/</guid>
      <description>V1.4.1 2020-04-17
 Updated Ottawa hospital census data to 2020-04-15. Minor changes to model parameters:  Current # of hospitalized patients changed from 43 to 37. Date of physical distancing implementation set to 2020-04-17.    V1.4.0 2020-04-16
 Updated Ottawa hospital census data to 2020-04-15. Changes to model parameters:  Doubling time changed from 5 days to 31.98 days based on observed doubling time in the last week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>Media contact: Michaela Schreiter, Media Relations Officer, The Ottawa Hospital, mschreiter@toh.ca ph: 613-222-7674
Science contacts: Doug Manuel dmanuel@ohri.ca, Warsame Yusuf waryusuf@ohri.ca, Alan Forster
Acknowledgements for website and content: Warsame Yusuf, Rostyslav Vyuha, Yulric Sequeira, Andrew Fitches, and others on Big Life Lab team.
Supporting Ottawa Public Health epidemiologist: Amira Ali, Jacqueline Willmore, Dara Spatz
Attribution: COVID-19 icons made by surang from www.flaticon.com.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roadmap</title>
      <link>/roadmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/roadmap/</guid>
      <description> The main purpose of this site is to visualize Ottawa-based projections for models performed by other teams.
 Review and update model parameters based on recent published studies. Priories for review:  ventilated patients deaths   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>