<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projections relatives à la COVID-19 à Ottawa on Ottawa COVID19</title>
    <link>/fr/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projections relatives à la COVID-19 à Ottawa on Ottawa COVID19</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/fr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Model parameters</title>
      <link>/fr/model/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/fr/model/</guid>
      <description>Projections are based on the reported daily hospital census for Ottawa.
 Daily hospital use reported by Ottawa Public Health.  Model parameters other than Ottawa hospital use are aligned with other models.
 Model parameters are described below.
 Parameter estimates are from COVID-19-MC and Tuite, Fisman, et al. models where possible, with updates based on Verity et al. (Lancet, March 20, 2020)* and Ferguson et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/fr/more/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/fr/more/</guid>
      <description>Utilisation des modèles Les projections s’utilisent principalement de deux manières :
Les projections à court terme (2 à 4 semaines) servent à connaître les besoins immédiats en services hospitaliers et en soins critiques pour les patients atteints de la COVID-19.
Les projections à long terme (6 semaines ou plus) servent à évaluer l’effet d’un relâchement de la distanciation physique.
 Précision des modèles Il est difficile de faire des projections précises à long terme sur la propagation de la COVID-19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changelog</title>
      <link>/fr/change-log/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/fr/change-log/</guid>
      <description>Updates involving only data updates will no longer be documented.
V3.0.0 2020-10-05
 Case data &amp;amp; projections have been added to the website. See model for more details on how projections for cases were created including input parameters. Ventilator &amp;amp; peak projections removed from website. Death figure removed from website.   V2.3.0 2020-08-05
 Projections use OPH hospitalization data from 07/07/2020 onwards. Updates to definitions.   V2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/fr/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/fr/contact/</guid>
      <description>Personne-ressource pour les médias : Michaela Schreiter, agente des relations avec les médias, L’Hôpital d’Ottawa. Courriel: mschreiter@toh.ca Téléphone : 613-222-7674
Personnes-ressources scientifiques : Doug Manuel dmanuel@ohri.ca, Warsame Yusuf waryusuf@ohri.ca, Alan Forster
Remerciements pour le site Web et le contenu : Warsame Yusuf, Rostyslav Vyuha, Yulric Sequeira, Andrew Fitches et les autres membres de l’équipe de Big Life Lab.
Avec le soutien des épidémiologistes de Santé publique Ottawa : Amira Ali, Jacqueline Willmore, Dara Spatz</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roadmap</title>
      <link>/fr/roadmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/fr/roadmap/</guid>
      <description>  The main purpose of this site is to visualize Ottawa-based projections for models performed by other teams.
 Review and update model parameters based on recent published studies. Priories for review:  ventilated patients deaths   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>